Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
Created time 14.10.27 13:38:11
★*********★
★忍者龟真人版：变种世代★
★< 孩子们你们是非比寻常的 >★
You are extraordinary, my sons.
★< 是世间绝无仅有的 >★
Unlike anything the world has ever seen.
★< 因伟大的使命而生 >★
Bound for greatness.
★< 去保护 >★
Destined to protect
★< 纽约的人民 >★
the people of New York.
★< 黑暗的力量正在崛起 >★
A dark force is growing.
★< 一个被人民称為"脚族"的犯罪组织 >★
A criminal organization known as the Foot Clan.
★< 他们的名称由来是因為他们 >★
So named because they step over
★< 无情的把市民们践踏在脚下 >★
the good people of this city with no regard.
★< 他们的领袖斯莱德 >★
Their leader, The Shredder,
★< 和他们的脚族部下们 >★
will come at you with ferocity.
★< 会兇狠的追杀你们 >★
His Foot Clan will outnumber you.
★< 你们将是纽约人民的 >★
The people of New York will look upon you
★< 唯一的希望 >★
as their only hope.
★< 集中精神 >★
Eyes focused.
★< 刻苦修行 >★
Elbows locked.
★< 隐匿於无形 >★
Stance low.
★< 要记住 >★
And we begin.
★< 我们的胜利 >★
Be one with the blades.
★< 来源於厚积薄发 >★
Lead their path.
★< 我知道你们急於给予敌人猛烈的回击 >★
I know you are eager to answer their calls,
★< 但是你们的训练还没有全部完成 >★
but your training is not yet complete.
★< 我们地下的世界必须保存希望的火种 >★
The world below must remain your home.
★< 作為你们的父亲， 你们必须相信我 >★
As your father, you must trust me.
★< 要沉住气 >★
Patience.
★< 沉住气 >★
★< 现在还不是你们出现的时机 >★
You're not yet ready to go above ground.
★< 但是我坚信当你们出现於 >★
But I believe when that day comes
★< 世人面前的时机来临时 >★
and you rise to the streets,
★< 你们一定要负责这 >★
you are going to be responsible
★< 不可思议的事 >★
for amazing things.
★瑞瓦德先生！★
Mr. Rivetti!
★瑞瓦德先生 瑞瓦迪先生，拜託你 ...★
Mr. Rivetti. Mr. Rivetti, please.
★我发誓你是我这辈子★
You're the most persistent human
★见过最顽固的人了★
I've ever met in my life, I swear.
★听著，我已经把我知道的所有一切都告诉了警察 懂吗?★
Look, I already told the cops everything, all right?
★但是也许你会有★
But maybe there's a detail
★漏掉一些地方没有告诉警察★
you could've forgotten to share with the police.
★亲爱的， 我不会忘记这种事情的★
Sweetheart, you don't forget something like that.
★10个人光天化日从天而降★
Ten guys storm in here, broad daylight,
★用枪指著我们叫我们趴下★
force us to the ground at gunpoint.
★然后拿走这些禁用化学品★
And these are restricted chemicals.
★而且还带走了一些脱氨基★
Benzyl cyanide and some deaminating agents, too.
★这些东西就算你在黑市上也买不到的★
You don't just buy this stuff, even on the black market.
★等等, 你刚说了脱氨基? 什麼脱氨基★
Wait, you said deaminating agents,
★这些是用於基因研究的★
those are used in genetic research.
★还有什麼其他人...★
Is there anybody else
★贩卖这些化学物质吗？除了你之外★
that's trafficking these sort of chemicals besides you?
★沿著这个港口有一个高度戒备的★
There's one other high-security facility
★监狱不是吗★
along this waterfront.
★但是他们不移动， 几乎像我们一样的很多的货物★
But they don't move nearly as much cargo as we do.
★欧尼尔, 我们30分鐘内就得走了， 快点阿!★
O'Neil! We're live in 30 minutes! Come on!
★呃...不、不，不， 稍等下，我马上回来★
Uh... No, no, no, I'll be right back.
★你在这等下，我马上就来★
Please don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.
★你简直就是想让我丢掉工作★
Come on, you're killing me.
★我是在工作啊★
I'm working.
★- 这根本就不是你的份内事 - 不是★
That's a paying job? No.
★因為我们有一个实际的支付工作★
Because we have an actual paying job.
★听著，你不会觉得这个城市★
Look, you don't think that every crime reporter
★每起犯罪都和「脚族」有关係吧？★
in the city has been trying to work this Foot Clan story?
★是的，我又有了新的发现★
I know that, but there is a new angle on this,
★就差这麼一点★
and I am this close to getting it.
★我就需要再问...★
I just need a couple of more...
★拜託，我们还是做好自己工作吧★
Let's just stick to what we're good at.
★快点我们出发了★
Let's stick to what we're good at. We're good at it.
★还有 5 秒， 4 秒...★
In five, four...
★嗨，观眾朋友大家好， 我是来自第6频道的艾波·欧尼尔★
Hi, guys, this is April O'Neil from Channel 6 News
★今天的纽约很美，同时，★
and I am here in beautiful New York City
★今天也是开春的第一天★
on the first day of spring.
★我们该甩掉★
And you know what that means.
★冬天累积的脂肪了★
It is time to shed that pesky winter weight.
★而在我身旁的★
And here with me today
★是知名健身教练哈利帕斯特纳 你好，哈利★
is celebrity fitness trainer Harley Pasternak. Hi, Harley.
★早上好，艾波★
Good morning, April.
★在我观察动物世界的20年裡， 我看过了★
Twenty years I've studied the animal kingdom.
★肥胖的猪，肥胖的牛★
There are fat pigs, there are fat cows.
★但是从来没有肥胖的鸟★
There are no fat birds.
★好的， 让我们来想像一隻性感的海鸥★
All right, I want you to visualize a sexy seagull.
★所以我们蹲下， 开始拍打我们的翅膀★
So we're going to squat down and flap your wings.
★尽全力把幅度做大， 完全的延长★
Right over there. Full extension.
★在脑海想像你离开远方的寒冬★
Picture you're leaving the cold north
★你在飞行，你在迁徙★
and you're flying. You're migrating.
★我上了四年的新闻专业， 现在就只能做这个★
Four years of journalism school so that I can do that.
★四年的大好青春，凡恩★
Four years of my life, Vern.
★实在是太无奈了★
It's embarrassing.
★我懂，艾波★
Look, O'Neil, I get it,
★你想要成為有专题新闻的大记者★
you want to be a serious journalist.
★★
I see you sniffing around the newsroom
★整天追著大新闻跑★
for the big stories.
★但是现在这样给予人们一些轻鬆的★
But it's also okay to just give people something
★像冰霜一样的消息也是不错的★
a little lighter. A little... Little froth.
★- 冰霜？ - 你想本来★
Froth? You know, how,
★咖啡就是平白无奇的咖啡★
when you get a coffee, it's just, like, coffee,
★但是当他们加上冰霜之后， 那喝起来就...★
then they put a little froth on it. It's kind of nice.
★凡恩，那是奶泡★
Vern, that's foam.
★是的、奶泡，冰霜， 反正就是这个意思★
Yes, foam, froth, you get the point.
★就是感觉很好， 味道也很好，就像糖果一样★
It's just... It's nice, it tastes good, it's candy.
★俗话说★
You ever heard the expression,
★" 不要和婴儿抢糖果吃 "★
"Never take candy from a baby"?
★那是因為就连他们都喜欢糖果！★
It's because even babies love candy!
★你给予人们这种美好的事物★
It's nice. And you're giving people
★这个行為本来就很美好★
something they like that's good and nice.
★他们看看你★
They look at you and they see,
★他们就觉得看到了美好的...★
"Wow, there's a nice... There's...
★糖果，重点是，我觉得★
"...candy." The point is, I think that
★你应该得到应有的奖励， 别太逼自己好吗？★
you should be rewarded, not punishing yourself. Okay?
★以及可以的话， 我想要奖励你一点东西★
And I'm... I'm prepared to reward you.
★我说我们就去我兄弟在城裡的饭馆吧★
I say that we go to my buddy's old restaurant downtown.
★那裡挺好的...★
It's very vibey...
★我们在街上随便吃就好了。★
We just ate on the way over here.
★我也不是说★
No, I know we just... I'm not saying
★要吃一顿完整的， 我们可以就点前菜★
for a full meal, we're just gonna eat appeteasers.
★我得去把那个採访搞定一下★
I got to go finish that interview.
★到时候办公室见，凡恩！★
I'll see you at the office, Vern!
★好吧 我会在办公室等你的！★
I will see you at the office!
★我只是想要跟你聊一下，瑞瓦迪先生。★
I just wanted to follow up, Mr. Rivetti.
★你不是在搞笑吧？ 你是怎麼知道我的号码的？★
Are you kidding me? How did you get my number?
★- 如果我能再问一个问题 - 我已经把所有我知道的都说了 - 等等★
Listen, I already told you everything I know about this crime, everything.
★这样吧，你还想打探什麼的话★
Okay, you wanna know anything else,
★就回去★
you go back down to the docks and you see
★找我的手下史丹， 他会告诉你★
my guy Stan. He'll tell you
★所有你需要知道的事情，可以了吧？★
anything else you need to know, okay?
★还有请高抬贵手★
And hey, do me a favor.
★把我的号码删了，好吗？★
Lose my number, all right?
★找到了★
Good. It's clear. Let's open it up.
★了解，我们把它打开搬出去★
Container's good. Move on to the next one.
★帮忙抬一下！★
Move it out! Get those to the trucks now!
★- 抬出去了 - 下个点！ 快点。★
Move out, next point! Go, go, go.
★第6频道，你好★
Channel 6. Chris.
★我是艾波，我正在码头这★
Chris, it's April. I'm at the docks.
★- 我们正在晚间报导当中，不管你有什麼消息都要等著 - 不，不，我需要...★
Whatever you got can wait for tomorrow. No, no, I need...
★一，二，放下！★
2-3-2, clear!
★- 别挡著我的路 - 是的★
- Get it out of my way. - Copy that.
★可恶★
Damn it.
★快搬★
Unit two, area three, move!
★动作快点！★
I've got movement!
★有人在这裡！★
Keep your eyes over here!
★11点方向！★
Weapons free!
★开火！★
Hold position!
★撤退！快撤退！★
Retreat! Retreat!
★快离开这裡！★
Get out of here!
★泰勒 泰勒！★
Taylor. Taylor!
★嗨，我正在和老妈SKYPE★
Hey. I'm Skyping with my mom.
★你不会相信我刚才看到了什麼★
You have no idea what I just went through.
★我吓坏了， 我看到了脚族被袭击★
I am freaking out. I saw a Foot Clan attack.
★你没事吧？★
Are you okay?
★我正在码头边上骑著脚踏车★
I was riding my bike by the docks.
★晚上很黑，★
It was night, it's dark already
★码头到处都是脚族的士兵★
and there are Foot Clan soldiers everywhere.
★接著也不到哪裡出来了一个傢伙★
Then out of nowhere, there was this guy
★攻击脚族的人★
fighting back against them.
★然后他还留下了一个符号★
And he... He left behind this symbol.
★我之前绝对见过★
And I know that I've seen it before.
★只是忘了在哪见过★
I can't remember where.
★那裡绝对有一个人在★
But there is someone fighting back
★对抗脚族★
against the Foot Clan.
★应该是存在一个这个城市的守护者★
There is a vigilante in this city.
★除了我之外没人知道★
And no one knows, but I do.
★既然我知道了， 我就终於有自己的新闻了★
I know. And now I have my story.
★对我来说， 再也不是那些起司跟奶泡的无聊杂事了★
There is no more froth and foam for me.
★你在说什麼？★
What?
★没事忘了吧★
Never mind.
★听好了，我们需要今晚报导的消息， 有谁有好点子吗？★
All right, we need a lead for tonight. Who's got it?
★对於曼哈顿商业区★
"Major redevelopments proposed
★- 的建设新主张？ - 不行★
"for lower Manhattan." No.
★我这裡有一个： 纽约警局因有效打击★
I got something. "NYPD task force taking credit
★脚族活动而受到褒奖★
"for small decline in Foot-related crime."
★- 我喜欢这个，我们就用这个吧 - 好的, 头儿★
I like that. Let's run with that. Yes, ma'am.
★★
7:00 AM broadcast,
we have three minutes to air.
★欧尼尔，我们下次再说吧★
Oh, O'Neil. I'll talk to you in a minute.
★没事，我知道★
I know that I'm actually overstepping
★其实估计一会我身边就会围满了人★
my boundaries by being here,
★所以你最好★
but I think that you're gonna
★你最好能留在这边，听听我要说的话★
I actually think that you're all gonna want to hear what I have to say.
★我昨晚目击了一起★
Um, I witnessed
★在布鲁克林码头★
an attempted Foot Clan robbery
★预谋的脚族劫案★
at the docks in Brooklyn last night.
★等等，监视器的确有记录到枪声★
Hold on, the scanner said that gunshots were heard,
★但是没有证据表示有脚族的活动痕跡★
but there were no reports of any Foot Clan activity.
★那是因為不管他们原计画是什麼★
That's because whatever they were
★他们都被人阻止了★
attempting to do was stopped.
★你在布鲁克林做什麼？★
What were you doing in Brooklyn anyway?
★那天那边有什麼夜市集会？★
Was there a trampoline convention?
★我之所以去布鲁克林★
I was in Brooklyn because I was reporting,
★是因為我不想坐在办公室无所事事★
not sitting behind my desk, McNaughton.
★好了，孩子们！★
Okay, kids!
★是谁阻止了脚族？★
Who stopped it?
★有个...★
Well, there was this guy.
★我没能看得非常清楚的人。。。 但他移动迅速★
I didn't see him clearly, but he was swinging
★他用货柜箱★
these giant shipping containers
★把脚族的士兵们都敲到了河裡去★
and knocking these guys into the... Into the river.
★一定有个隐密的守护者在对抗著脚族★
There is a vigilante that is fighting back
★这裡面绝对包含大新闻★
against the Foot Clan. There's a huge story here!
★欧尼尔， 我想你一定是看到了超人，太酷了★
O'Neil, I think you found Superman. That's cool.
★这个守护者是真实存在的， 我亲眼看到了★
The vigilante is real. I saw him.
★欧尼尔，我假设你不会只是上来★
O'Neil, I'm gonna assume
★跟我们说这个天方夜谭的故事★
that you would not come up here and tell us
★你总得有点什麼证据来证明吧★
this fantastic story without some tangible proof.
★我只拍到这张照片， 这个记号是画在一个货柜箱上的★
I took this photo of one of the shipping containers.
★事实上我觉得这是他故意留给我们的★
I actually think that it may be his calling card.
★这根本不算什麼阿，欧尼尔， 这什麼都不是！★
This is nothing, O'Neil. This is nothing!
★我想说的就是这个，有人★
That's exactly the point. Somebody
★阻止了脚族的抢劫★
stopped a Foot robbery and left no evidence.
★并没有留下任何证据★
There is nothing.
★哦，我懂了★
Oh, I get it.
★你想让我在晚间新闻裡★
You wanted me to put "nothing"
★- 就什麼都不说 - 当然不是★
on the nightly news. Of course not.
★好了，我会假装我们没有过这一段对话的★
You know, I'm gonna pretend we never had this conversation.
★我现在就把她从我的脑子裡删除★
I'm erasing it from my mind.
★剩下的人都回去工作吧★
And the rest of us, we're gonna go back to work.
★好了 干正事吧★
Let's hit it!
★观眾朋友大家好， 欢迎收看第6频道早间新闻★
Hello, everybody. Welcome to the Channel 6 Morning News.
★关於新的防护法案★
New developments in that ongoing sanitation strike
★有了更多进展★
to tell you about.
★但是首先， 在和警局局长审视了★
But first, after reviewing the city's
★城市的犯罪情况之后★
soaring crime rates with the police commissioner,
★参议院丹莱格在市政厅门外， 步出了市政厅的大门★
Councilman Dan Gregor took to the steps of City Hall,
★重申了政府★
reaffirming the city's commitment
★对於打击犯罪集团★
to fight against the rising crime organization
★脚族的决心和承诺★
calling themselves the Foot Clan.
★通过与萨克斯先生和★
He did so on the heels of a renewed
★萨克斯集团的合作来巩固这一承诺★
contract with Eric Sacks and Sacks Industries.
★利用萨克斯集团的研发和安保技术★
Using the Sacks research and securities technology,
★这座城市拥有了更多的把握★
this city greatly improves its chances
★将脚族绳之於法★
of bringing the Foot Clan to justice!
★开始★
★你的人都是弱者★
★任务失败, 并不令我惊讶★
★我们在码头被那个守护者袭击了★
We couldn't have anticipated the vigilante
★许瑞德先生★
showing up at the docks, Master Shredder.
★你连这种小事都没办法处理★
★我们从来没见过这样的敌人★
But we've never seen an enemy like this.
★他们的大小★
Their size.
★他们的力量★
Their strength.
★他们绝不是人类★
They're not human.
★我从来不相信什麼神话故事★
I don't believe in fairy tales.
★这也就是為什麼社会想要消灭脚族的原因★
It's what society wants to reduce the Foot Clan to.
★我们是一段神话★
A myth.
★脚族会★
But the Foot Clan
★重新崛起的★
will rise again.
★把守护者给我抓住★
Capture the vigilantes however you can.
★去用无辜的市民当作诱饵★
Use innocent people as bait.
★绝对没有人能够阻挡我们★
No one will stop us in our quest
★重夺胜利的道路★
to reclaim victory.
★我们将要掌控这座城市★
We will own this city.
★女士先生们★
Ladies and gentlemen, please join me
★请和我一起欢迎纽约警局的首要赞助人★
in welcoming the NYPD's top benefactor,
★艾瑞克?萨克斯★
Eric Sacks.
★过奖了，过奖了★
Please, please. Please.
★请坐下，请坐下★
Sit down, sit down.
★我必须得说★
I have to say,
★今晚能够在这裡看到这麼多人， 实在是太美妙了★
it's wonderful to see so many people out here tonight,
★尤其是在这样一座★
especially in a neighborhood
★脚族犯罪猖獗的城市裡★
so hard hit by the Foot's crime wave.
★多年以前， 我的生活也因為悲剧而改变★
Years ago, my life was touched by tragedy.
★那时我是在世界顶尖的★
I was a young scientist
★科学团队工作的年轻科学家★
working with a world-class team
★进行绝对创新的研究上★
on cutting-edge research.
★但是我们的实验室被攻击了★
And our laboratory was attacked,
★资料被销毁器材被烧光★
set fire to, robbed,
★就是被脚族的那群懦夫★
by the cowards that call themselves the Foot Clan.
★一些我的受僱人员★
Several of my employees
★在那一天牺牲了生命★
lost their lives that day.
★他们死的光荣， 会被我们所铭记★
And it is in their honor, in their memory,
★萨克斯集团， 旗下萨克斯生技★
that Sacks Industries, whether through Sacks Biomed,
★机械和建筑公司★
Sacks Robotics or Sacks Construction,
★将继续履行承诺，永远守护纽约★
to keeping the city of New York, our city,
★保护我们的城市安全寧静★
safe.
★所以不论是谁， 想要将罪恶之火烧到这座城市★
So whenever someone takes flame to this city,
★我就会出现在那，给予他正义的制裁★
I will be there to put the fire out.
★这是我的承诺★
And that's a promise.
★谢谢★
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
★萨克斯先生， 我是艾波?欧尼尔★
Great work, sir. Very inspirational.
★我父亲曾经和你共事过★
Mr. Sacks. April O'Neil. You worked with my father.
★哦！★
Oh!
★我完全无法相信，我自从...★
I can't believe it. I haven't seen you since...
★自从他的葬礼就没见过我★
Since his funeral.
★那已经是很久以前了★
It was a long time ago.
★是的★
Yeah.
★只是想要告诉你★
I just wanted to tell you that your words
★你的演讲让我很有共鸣★
really resonated with me, and I hope to one day
★我希望有一天也能够对这个城市★
contribute to the city in the way that you do.
★做出有如你这样的贡献★
Well, it looks like you're doing a pretty good job.
★好吧★
Channel 6, very impressive, April.
★这位记者你的抱负不错， 我完全受宠若惊★
Um... Thank you. It's, uh...
★谢谢，确实很多事情都事与愿委★
It isn't exactly everything I anticipated it would be.
★只要你能够保持真我★
As long as you are true to yourself,
★你的父亲都会為你感到骄傲的★
your father will always be proud of you.
★- 萨克斯先生， 你得在7点抵达市郊地区★
Mr. Sacks, we have to be uptown at 7:00.
★我们有机会再见★
I'll see you on TV.
★艾瑞克?萨克斯的话实在是太鼓舞人心了★
Eric Sacks was so inspiring.
★我知道这才是那些具有价值的新闻★
I know this is a story that actually matters.
★就像你那个超级英雄报导？★
The superhero one?
★好吧好主意，我们就跟踪报导吧★
That's a good idea. I should chase that down.
★大家怎麼都在跑？★
Where's everybody going?
★- 欧尼尔! 你去哪??? - 嗨★
- O'Neil! Where are you going? - Hey.
★- 等一下 艾波！ - 嗨★
April! Hey!
★你是从哪边跑出来的? 请等等★
What are you running from? Wait, wait!
★监视器拍到大量脚足家族活动★
Shots fired, Broadway and Centre Street.
★他们挟持了人质，兄弟★
Heavy Foot Clan activity at the Broad Street platform.
★你知道我们不应该暴露在公眾视线底下★
But you know we're not supposed to go above ground.
★我们之前已经破戒了， 就让事情有始有终吧★
We started something, we gotta finish it.
★这实在是太疯狂了★
This is insane.
★那隻猫竟然在用筷子玩钢琴！★
That cat is playing  Chopsticks with chopsticks!
★别在天兵了★
Don't be an idiot.
★- 喔 - 好了★
- Aw. - Okay.
★我们出发吧，伙计们！★
Let's rock 'n' roll, boys!
★跑快点！★
Run!
★快逃！★
Get out!
★快走，快走！★
Go, go!
★如果你不想死★
If you want to live, do it! Go on!
★继续往下走★
Just stay down!
★到底下这裡！★
Get over here!
★继续走！★
Keep moving!
★趴在地上！★
Keep your hands where I can see them!
★移动到这边★
Move to the side.
★- 是炸弹 - 闭嘴！★
- They're bombs. - Shut up!
★那边的！★
On the ground!
★所有人不许动！★
Nobody move!
★我们知道你们就在附近★
We know you're out there!
★如果你们不投降， 我们就开始处决人质★
If you don't surrender, we start executing hostages!
★把头低下！★
Get your head down! Don't move!
★让我再告诉你一遍 你这个懦夫！★
Don't make me tell you again! Not a word!
★怎样，别这样看著我！★
Don't look at me!
★别这样！ 别这样做！★
Don't! Don't do it!
★你！★
You!
★给我站起来！★
Stand up!
★他们来了！★
All aboard!
★我们上去!★
On your 12!
★移动！★
Come on!
★做的好★
That's right.
★★
Like a shadow, bra.
★我们上去，移动！★
Let's go! Let's move!
★- 你看到那是什麼了吗? - 他们从这裡爬上去了★
Right here. Some kind of freak!
★感觉像是什麼生物！★
There were a couple of them!
★就在上面★
Whoo! Right past me!
★就在上面, 天哪★
They saved us.
★快进去，进去，进去!★
Go, go, go!
★站住！ 别动！★
Let's go, guys! Both sides!
★是的，就是我说的！★
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about!
★★
Yeah, boys, bring it in.
★令人难以置信的！★
That was amazing. You were incredible!
★漂亮的肘击，多尼★
Great elbow, Donnie.
★没错！ 那就是我说的★
Oh, yeah! That's what I'm talking about.
★这是我们的城市！ 这些是我们的街道！★
This is our city! These are our streets!
★这样就对了嘛★
You mess with us, you step into
★★
the Wu, whoo, Tang!
★是的！ 你有见到那个人吗★
Ooh, yeah! Did you see that guy's
★就像在树林中潜行★
jaw connect with the concrete?
★你看到我刚才在火车之间穿梭了吗！★
He'll be drinking out of a sippy cup for months!
★我就是说这个，兄弟★
Ah, that's what I'm talking about, brothers.
★我就像是暗夜中的黑影，来去无踪★
Like shadows in the night. Completely unseen.
★- 那是什麼? - 是相机的闪光... - 我们知道那是快门声★
It's a camera flash.
★是谁拍的照片？★
Who's behind the camera flash?
★根据我的推测是一个女的★
By my calculations, it's a girl.
★- 我们要杀了她吗 - 你说什麼？ -我们可以温柔地杀★
Give her some flowers, earn her trust.
★- 你不能滥用你的力量，这件事我来搞定 - 别，别，到这来★
I got this. Raph, no, no, no! Come on!
★- 把相机给我★
Give me the camera.
★- 你们看...他又在学蝙蝠侠讲话了★
Ooh, look, he's doing his Batman voice.
★他长得实在太火辣了， 我感觉我的壳都硬起来了★
She's so hot, I can feel my shell tightening.
★我们能听得到你淫荡的心声★
We can hear you!
★如果你不把相机给我， 我就会...★
If you don't give me the camera, I'm gonna...
★够了！★
Enough!
★- 拉斐尔，别多嘴 - 靠 ...★
Back off, Raph.
★我好不容易能当一次蝙蝠侠★
I only saw Batman once!
★女士你好，我诚挚向你道歉★
Ma'am, hello. I apologize.
★我的兄弟刚才忘记对你稍微客气一点了★
My colleague here forgot to say "please."
★所以★
So,
★现在可以请你把相机给我们吗？★
would you please hand over the camera?
★不要怕...不要怕★
No, no, no, no. Whoa.
★放心，没事的，这只是面具★
Whoa. Chill. It's just a mask. See? Don't freak out.
★看吧★
Right?
★啊！★
Ah!
★我觉得你这招的确是奏效了★
Oh, I think that went well.
★呼吸定态，血压稳定★
Breathing steady. Blood pressure stabilizing.
★- 情况稳定 - 爱因斯坦又在演医生了★
Why are we still here playing doctor?
★他好不容易有这机会★
She may have a head injury.
★恭喜你阿，这次的病人还是个女神★
Uh, correction. She's a hot chick
★唤醒他是保护★
who may have a head injury, which makes it
★- 城市的责任 - 女士? 女士?★
- our civic duty to... - Ma'am, ma'am.
★你能听见我说话吗？ 知道你在哪座城市吗？★
Can you hear me? Do you know what city you're in?
★你知道你在哪裡吗？★
Do you know where you are?
★你曾经看过那个一隻小猫★
Have you seen that video where the cat
★用筷子玩钢琴的视频吗？★
plays  Chopsticks with the chopsticks?
★你能别在这边捣乱吗？★
Can we focus here?
★伙计们, 别这样， 给他留点空间★
Guys, please! Come on. Give her some air.
★你们到底是什麼？★
What are you?
★好吧，小姐★
Well, Miss,
★我们是忍者★
uh, we're ninjas.
★也是变种人★
We're mutants.
★基本上我们就是乌龟★
Well, technically, we're turtles.
★而且是青少年！★
Oh, and we're teenagers!
★但妳要聊成人话题也是可以啦★
But we can still have adult conversations.
★等等，这是...★
Wait, wait, wait. So...
★所以你们是...★
You're...
★忍者，变种，★
Ninja, mutant,
★乌龟，青少年？★
turtle, teenagers?
★妳这样讲听起来很搞笑耶★
Well, when you put it like that, it sounds ridiculous!
★你看吧， 他看我们就跟看怪胎一样★
See, she's looking at us like we're freaks.
★我猜这就是你要拍我们的原因对吧？★
I bet that's why you took our picture, wasn't it?
★可以展示给你的朋友们看？★
To show your friends?
★这是件好事！ 也许他还认识其他女神★
Bro, that's a good thing! Maybe she has hot friends.
★- 你在找这个吗？ - 别摔坏它★
Looking for this? Don't break it.
★不不不不，请不要★
No, no, no. Please.
★我要跟你说多少次？★
How many times do I have to tell you?
★我们不破坏东西， 我们只会摆平它们★
We don't break things, we fix them.
★多尼的话早就把这手机格式化了★
Donnie already wiped the phone, genius.
★问题就解决了，你这蠢蛋★
Problem solved, moving on.
★谁知道呢 他没让你在这发号施令★
And who put you in charge? You know who did.
★- 你怎麼知道他不会 - 喔 好紧张的气氛阿★
Ooh, tension! It's been like 30 whole minutes
★你们在这边吵吵闹闹都半小时了★
since you guys had this argument.
★李奥纳多★
Leonardo, if we want to make it home before Master,
★差不多该结束这场争执了吧★
we gotta hustle.
★李奥纳多？★
Leonardo?
★别把妳看到的说出去★
Do not say a word about this to anyone.
★如果你走漏了？ 我们会来找你★
If you do, we will find you.
★艾波?欧尼尔★
April O'Neil.
★我们回去了，拉斐尔★
We're on the move, Raphael.
★拉斐尔？★
Raphael?
★是啊！★
Yeah!
★我们会来找你，欧尼尔★
We'll find you, O'Neil.
★拍谢★
I'm sorry, that came across
★我说的感觉好像一个怪叔叔★
super creepy, okay?
★但我们会来找你的★
We will find you, though.
★- 耶！ - 真是棒阿，伙计！★
I was on fire, bro!
★你们知道吗？★
Did you see me back there?
★他可以排我心目中的女神前两位！★
Guys, I totally talked to a girl!
★闭嘴，米奇！★
Shut up, Mikey!
★耶，哥们！★
Yeah, bra!
★米奇，刚才你放屁吧？★
Mikey, was that you?
★呵呵被发现了★
Pepperoni.
★李奥纳多... 我就知道是这样★
Leonardo. I know those names. I know those names.
★拉斐尔，李奥纳多...★
Raphael, Raphael. Leonardo.
★晚上好★
Good evening.
★我是艾波·欧尼尔★
This is April O'Neil,
★正在我爸爸的实验室裡录影★
reporting live from my daddy's lab.
★我知道这听起来可能很无聊★
I know it sounds pretty boring,
★但实际上他做的东西非常酷★
but actually, he does some pretty cool stuff.
★把录影机关了，艾波★
Time to put the camera away, April.
★喔不，爸爸！★
Aw, Dad!
★你们好，我将给你们展示...★
And now I will show you
★非常奇妙的东西★
something amazing.
★这是从另一个宇宙星球★
It's supposed to be from a different planet
★得来的电视★
in outer space! Here we go.
★啊！★
Ah!
★萨克斯先生★
Mr. Sacks,
★你现在正在进行的是什麼实验呢？★
what sort of experiments are you doing here?
★这真是很难回答的问题★
Oh, that's a very complicated question.
★我们正在企图改变世界★
We're trying to change the world.
★来看著镜头★
Look at the camera!
★你好，史林特★
Hello, Splinter.
★而这些是我的小乌龟们， 这是李奥纳多★
And these are my little turtles, Leonardo,
★拉斐尔，★
Raphael,
★米开朗基罗，以及多纳太罗★
Michelangelo and Donatello.
★我们来看看你★
The fans want to see you!
★我就知道是这样★
I knew it.
★那些守护者，我看到他们了 我看到他们了★
The vigilante, I saw him. I saw them! I saw them.
★我认识他们， 当我还是小女孩的时候★
I've known them since I was a little girl.
★他们都是我的宠物★
They were my pets.
★他们是我儿时的宠物，★
They were my childhood pets,
★还都是以文艺復兴时期 知名艺术家的名子命名的★
and they were named after Italian Renaissance painters.
★天啊，我还是回房间裡面吧★
Mom, I want to move back home.
★他在这裡吗？★
Is he here?
★我没看到他的影子★
I don't see him.
★多尼？★
Donnie?
★等著，根据我的计算有74%的成功率★
My thermal scans indicate there's a 74% variable
★但是同时有61%的概率是他在躲猫猫★
that there's a 61% chance he's not...
★他不在这裡★
That he's not here, guys.
★没事没事，他不在这裡★
That he's not here.
★好了，跟著我★
Okay.
★我们...偷偷...溜进去★
Fall in, quietly.
★嘘★
Dude.
★兄弟们，我要把那个妹★
So, guys, if it wasn't already obvious with that girl,
★他是我的★
dibs.
★如果被史林特师父抓包★
If Master Splinter catches us,
★他一定会处罚我们★
he'll send us back to the Ha'shi.
★我才不要被处罚★
I ain't going back to the Ha'shi.
★每次还不都是因為你★
Every time we're in the Ha'shi, it's because of you.
★你们不用再担心★
Well, bro, you won't have to worry about me
★我会拖你们下水★
dragging you down anymore.
★你这话是什麼意思？★
What's that supposed to mean?
★有机会我会搬出去住★
I'm going out on my own. First chance I get.
★这样我们的嘻哈圣诞专辑怎麼办？★
How are we gonna finish our hip-hop Christmas album, bro?
★你是负责炒热气氛的耶！★
You're the hype man!
★- 闭嘴啦 - 你才闭嘴 - 闭嘴★
Shut up.
★- 安静 - 安静★
★- 有口水喷到我的眼睛了★
I got glop in my eye.
★他哪都不会去的， 我们到哪都不分开的★
Shh! He's not going anywhere. We all stick together.
★对不起刚口水喷到你★
Sorry I spit in your eye, bro.
★兄弟们...★
Shh! Guys? Guys.
★我们有麻烦了...★
We got a bogey.
★呃...★
Uh...
★你们去哪了？★
Where have you been?
★我们一直都在...★
We weren't...
★我有东西忘了拿了！★
I forgot to soak my retainer!
★你看★
I'm totally sleepwalking!
★米奇正在梦游，正在离开！★
Look, Mikey's sleeping and walking.
★他可是完全无辜的啊★
He's totally innocent.
★够了！ 你们违反不能任意在人前出现的规定★
Enough! You disobeyed a direct order.
★发生什麼事了？★
Why did you go above ground? What happened?
★非常好★
Very well.
★如果这就是你们所以期望发生的事情★
If that's how it's going to be,
★通通进去！★
to the Ha'shi!
★欧尼尔，什麼事情需要叫我到这来？★
O'Neil! All right, what was so important I had to get here?
★- 好的，你準备好了吗? - 是的 随时★
Okay. Are you ready? Yeah.
★好的★
Okay. You know how
★- 你知道我之前说过守护者的故事 - 是的★
I saw the vigilante? Yeah.
★只是当时我没有任何照片证据★
But I had no photos or evidence to show you,
★所以听起来很疯狂★
so I just sounded crazy.
★- 是的 - 这一次我又见到他们了★
Yes. Okay. But I saw him again.
★我之所以说"他们"★
Well, I didn't see him again,
★是因為总共有4个★
I saw them, because there's four.
★不是一个，是4个， 我需要你把这★
There's not just one, there's four. And I was standing
★做為我的独家新闻★
as close to them as you are to me right now.
★他们长什麼样？★
What'd they look like?
★我现在可以告诉你★
I'll show you.
★什麼？★
What?
★就是这个★
Like this.
★像乌龟？★
Like turtles?
★不是看起来像乌龟★
Well, they don't look like turtles
★因為他们就是乌龟★
because they are turtles.
★每个都有身高一米八还会说话★
They're over six feet tall and they speak English.
★天阿★
Oh, my God.
★我熬了一整夜，等等，我都通宵了★
I was awake all night, please look, I was awake all night
★过去三个月犯罪新闻★
googling all of the thwarted crimes
★所有类似乌龟跡象活动的★
over the past three months, and this symbol
★这个符号出现在每一个犯罪现场★
appeared at every single one.
★你看！ 每一个都有★
Look! Every single one of them.
★看这， 在这裡，在这裡，在这裡，在这裡，在这裡★
This one, look. Here, here, here, here, here.
★这是日本古代的符号， 象徵著家庭★
And it's an ancient Japanese symbol that means "family."
★等等，我的电脑呢★
Wait, it's on my laptop.
★我的天 我不相信这就是真相！★
I can't believe you brought me in to do this!
★对在这，就在这★
It's here, it's here.
★这是我爸以前的实验室★
This is my father's lab.
★这是相同的实验室★
This is the same lab
★那隻老鼠跟这些乌龟★
where these things were born
★就是在这出现的...★
or created or mutated.
★变种...★
Or, I don't know the terminology,
★你可以认真听我说吗?★
but will you please just look at what
★这些都能连起来★
I'm showing you and listen to me. It's all connected.
★这些乌龟就是守护者★
The turtles are the vigilantes
★守护者也就是这些乌龟★
and the vigilantes are these turtles.
★你看，这是香肠起司披萨★
Pizza has cheese,
★你要快点吃阿，你要补充营养的★
tomato sauce, all your favorite stuff.
★它们不吃这个的★
Eat it. You guys need nutrition. Or not.
★我来整理一下★
I just want to be clear.
★你现在就是想跟我说， 现在有...★
You are now telling me that there are
★4个一米八高的乌龟还会说话★
four six-foot talking turtles walking around New York City,
★在纽约走来走去， 其他人都没看到就只有你遇到了？★
and no one has seen them but you?
★没错! 这就是我要说的★
That's what I'm telling you.
★我不是故意要笑★
I don't mean to laugh,
★我们还需要知道什麼？★
but is there anything else we should know about them?
★他们都是忍者★
They're ninjas.
★你说什麼？★
I'm sorry, what?
★他们也是忍者★
And they do karate.
★OK，你可以滚了★
Okay, get out.
★欧尼尔！★
O'Neil!
★这不算是最糟的★
It could have been worse.
★我刚被炒魷鱼，还有什麼更糟的？★
I just got fired, Vern. How could it be worse?
★这不一定是坏事， 你可以利用这段时间好好★
Maybe it's good. Maybe you should take a little time,
★照顾下自己★
take care of yourself.
★来吧，我送你一程★
Come on, let me give you a ride.
★除非你能带我去萨克斯公司★
Not unless you're going to the Eric Sacks estate.
★我不做其他无聊的报导★
April... Hey! I'm not giving up on this story.
★你得放下手★
You gotta put that to bed.
★你曾经认识的那些著名报导人员★
Would all of those other great reporters
★他们会放弃吗?★
that you worked with, would they have "put it to bed"?
★那不一样★
No. That's different.
★那怎麼不一样了？★
How is it different?
★他们都是从我这样的困境裡出来的， 对吧?？★
They all started exactly where I am, right?
★我只好开著第6频道的新闻车，★
I'm not driving the Channel 6 news van
★送你去萨克斯公司了★
onto the Sacks estate.
★- 谁让你这麼做的? - 是你阿★
Who asked you to do that? Uh, you did.
★如果你能说声谢谢那就更好了★
And a "thanks" would have been nice.
★或许哪天你才是那个应该感谢我的人★
Maybe one day you're gonna be thanking me.
★你去找艾瑞克?萨克斯想做什麼？★
So, what do you want with Eric Sacks?
★我爸爸曾经為他工作★
My dad used to work for him.
★他是唯一一个可以证明我★
He's the only person that's gonna be able
★到底是不是疯了的人★
to tell me whether or not I'm crazy.
★為什麼疯了？★
Crazy about what?
★我才不想让你笑我★
I don't need you to laugh at me also.
★说吧，欧尼尔★
Oh, come on, O'Neil.
★这是最后一次採访了★
This is the Fenwick Express, it's a
★在这裡我们一视同仁， 一个非常安全的环境★
judgment-free zone. A cocoon of safety.
★你保证？★
Promise?
★我希望这是值得你去作★
I'm insulted that you would suggest otherwise.
★你们处罚经过11小时了★
Ooh, 11 hours in the Ha'shi.
★你们打算对於昨晚发生的★
Are you sure none of you want to tell me
★事情一个字都不说吗？★
where you were last night?
★你在三轮车上怎麼样？★
How you holding up, fellas?
★啊！ 我不会摔下的不会的★
Ah! I ain't breaking if Donnie ain't breaking.
★他是不会摔下的★
Experiencing intense nausea but not breaking.
★伙伴们？ 我现在已经找到平衡点了！★
Guys? I'm in the zone!
★不过我快脑充血了！★
There is literally nothing that could break me right now!
★披萨来了★
Starting to break.
★你们肯定都吃过五味起司披萨★
Of course, you've all tasted the five-cheese pizza.
★但是我这盒 ...★
But this,
★是所有起司商人★
cheesemongers have speculated
★花了数百年都无法确认的珍宝★
of its existence for centuries.
★集合了眾多高人尽情烹製★
Da Vinci's original masterpiece.
★我来向你们展示 ...★
I submit to you...
★有99种起司的披萨★
...the 99-cheese pizza.
★哦！★
Oh!
★这是不可能的★
It's not possible.
★米奇，这是个陷阱！★
Mikey, it's a trap! A pizza with that variety
★一个披萨能放那麼多种起司绝对不合理的！★
of cheese is a culinary impossibility!
★你要我举例一下裡面的起司成分吗★
Shall I list the ingredients? No.
★切达起司★
Cheddar...
★- 波萝伏洛起司 - 米奇，你别去看它！★
Provolone... Mikey, don't you do it!
★大概你不知道的起司★
Asiago...
★一起保存它！★
Keep it together!
★塔莱焦起司★
Taleggio...
★- 要坚持住阿! 千万要忍住阿 - 我根本都没听过这种披萨★
I don't even know what that is.
★当然肯定有莫扎里拉起司★
Mozzarella, of course.
★好，好！我们离开★
All right, all right, all right! We left the lair
★是因為脚族绑架人质★
because the Foot were taking hostages
★我们去狠狠教训他们★
and we kicked some serious butt,
★但是被一个★
and there was this girl named April O'Neil
★叫做欧尼尔的女孩拍到照片★
who took our picture,
★但是我们已经把事情摆平了★
but we took care of it.
★你这蠢货★
Idiot.
★不，我最坏的设想成真了★
Oh, no, my worst fears have been realized.
★别担心了，没什麼事的！★
Don't worry about it. Donnie erased the picture!
★我们又不会有什麼危险★
We're not in danger.
★不，现在有危险的是 艾波?欧尼尔！★
No. It's April O'Neil who is in danger!
★把那个女孩找到，把他带到这裡来★
Find the girl. Bring her here.
★但是，师父，你说不去...★
But,  sensei, you said to not go...
★找到那个女孩！★
Find the girl!
★遵命，找到那个女孩★
Find the girl.
★这就是我告诉汤普森的故事， 然后他就把我开除了★
That's what I told Thompson and she fired me.
★所以他们是外星人？★
So they're aliens?
★这麼说太蠢了★
No, that's stupid.
★他们是忍者★
They're reptiles.
★我想他们是在帮助市民★
They help people, I guess.
★是你把那些小动物养大★
Heroes in the half-shell.
★- 是阿 - 我觉得这也说不是很疯狂...★
Okay. Come on. It's not that crazy.
★动物的世界裡...充满了...★
I... The animal kingdom is full of...
★譬如可以双脚站立走路的狗★
I used to have a dog that could moonwalk.
★谢谢你送我来★
Thanks for the ride, Vern.
★小事一桩★
Yeah. No problem.
★没有什麼比★
Nothing better than
★把一个美女， 送到富商的家门口更闷了...★
dropping off a pretty girl at a rich guy's house.
★你好，我是艾波?欧尼尔 我来这见艾瑞克?萨克斯★
Hi, it's April O'Neil, here to see Eric Sacks.
★艾波，没想到那麼快就看到你★
April's arrived early this year.
★很抱歉我突然来访，萨克斯先生★
I'm sorry to barge in on you like this, Mr. Sacks.
★没关係，别太过意不去★
No, no, no. Please, please.
★谢谢你★
Thank you.
★我正在做一个独家新闻★
I've been working on a story.
★关於对抗脚族★
And I have this theory that there are these vigilantes
★的城市守护者★
that are fighting back against the Foot.
★我想你和我爸爸， 应该是曾经创造出他们的人★
I think you and my father may have created them.
★我...我不太确定你说的...★
Uh, I'm not sure I...
★请你务必告诉我， 关於那个研究的所有细节★
Can you please tell me everything that you know
★关於文艺復兴计画？★
about Project Renaissance?
★★
Hmm.
★好吧...它...就是一个梦想★
Well, um, it was a dream.
★一场随你的父亲去世就破灭的梦想★
A dream that died with your father.
★如果它并没有灭亡呢？★
What if it isn't dead?
★那是不可能的★
That's impossible.
★那场大火中， 我们失去所有的研究资料★
We lost all our research in the fire,
★设备，所有东西，每件事物★
all our specimens, everything.
★我过去的15年之间★
I've spent the last 15 years
★都在试图重新复製当年的成果★
trying to replicate the results.
★那场大火你并没有失去所有★
You didn't lose everything in the fire.
★这不可能是真的★
This can't be real.
★这就是真的★
It is real.
★我看到了他们4个★
I saw all four of them.
★你真的想知道研究项目的事情吗？★
Do you really want to know about Project Renaissance?
★- 是的 - 跟我来★
Yes. Come with me.
★我出生在日本冲绳的军事基地★
I was born in Japan, at a military base in Okinawa.
★我父亲去了越南★
My father went to Vietnam.
★就再也没有回来★
Didn't come back.
★我在战争外就是一个局外人★
I was an outsider in a foreign land.
★我吓坏了★
A freak.
★我是一个绝望无助的小男孩★
I was a powerless and helpless boy.
★直到当地的师父收养我★
Until a local  sensei took me under his wing.
★是他救了我★
And he saved me.
★传授我课业， 也就是之后我与你父亲共享的知识★
Taught me lessons that I later shared with your father.
★日本，第9世纪时★
Ninth-century Japan.
★一个邪恶君主在全国各地★
An evil warlord ruled the land.
★水源裡下毒， 带来了黑暗的年代★
He poisoned the water supply, bringing on the dark ages.
★死亡，疾病，民不聊生★
Death and disease and suffering ran rampant.
★就像脚族★
Not unlike the Foot Clan
★这样残害城市★
and what they'd like to do to our city.
★直到有一天，英雄出现了★
Then one day, a hero arose.
★研发出能够治癒君主★
A great alchemist discovered the antidote
★下毒的疫苗★
to the warlord's poison.
★可是英雄不是天生的★
The cure-all
★而是被创造出来的★
for his evil.
★你的父亲和我正在尝试 重现万灵药★
Your father and I were trying to recreate that cure-all.
★我们研发了疫苗★
We developed a mutagen
★能够刺激的生物自我疗復★
capable of stimulating self-repair
★精细到个体细胞的层面上★
on a cellular level.
★你们打算拿那个做什麼？★
What were you going to do with it?
★试想一下如果纽约★
Imagine New York City,
★被生化武器攻击★
being victim to a chemical attack.
★然而这种解药， 将会完全抵御这种攻击★
This mutagen would be able to reverse its effects.
★将会拯救城市，拯救人民★
It would save the city, it would save the people.
★这些实验物品，这些乌龟★
Those test subjects, those turtles...
★他们体内流动的是★
Running in their blood
★那次实验唯一留下来的成果了★
is the last of this precious mutagen.
★在你告诉我之前★
And up until a few moments ago,
★我还以為我们失败了★
I thought we failed.
★我以為他们都在那场大火中丧生了★
I thought they died in the fire. How...
★他们怎麼可能活下来的？★
How could they have lived?
★因為是我救了他们★
Because I saved them.
★当然，你的确会去救★
Of course you did.
★艾波，这些基因隐藏了巨大的能量★
April, the mutagen possesses powers
★远远超过我们的想像★
beyond our wildest hopes.
★不论你需要什麼资源★
Whatever resources you need,
★告诉我★
I'm here.
★让我们一起努力找到他们吧★
Let's work together. We'll find them.
★改写人类的歷史， 就完全寄託在他们身上了★
The course of human history may depend on it.
★我想你会理解的★
I'll show you out.
★嘿！ 艾波！★
Bam! You've been hacked!
★我是多纳太罗★
By Donatello. Remember me?
★那隻乌龟， 还记得我吧？听到我说话吗★
Turtle. Four eyes. But enough about me.
★我说过我们会找到你的★
We told you we'd find you. Meet us here.
★来这个地点，自己一个人来★
And come alone. Or... Or else we're...
★如果你不照做...你会被惩罚的★
You shall be punished and stuff.
★有人吗？★
Hello?
★是你们叫我来这边的★
You told me to come here.
★我自己一个人来的★
I didn't bring anyone with me.
★我完全按照你们的要求...★
I did exactly...
★好的！ 你就是 艾波?欧尼尔吗？★
Okay! Are you April O'Neil?
★啟动视网膜扫描★
Initiating retinal scan.
★扫瞄，扫瞄 扫瞄，扫瞄★
Scanning, scanning, scanning, scanning.
★扫描完毕， 是她，确定是她★
Scan complete. It's her. It's her. Guys, it's her!
★当然是她，多尼★
Of course it's her, Donnie.
★嘿 你好阿 难以置信你真的自己来这了★
Hey. Really glad you could make it.
★我们今天要给你★
Hey. There's someone important
★介绍一个新的人认识， 但是首先...★
we want to introduce you to, but first...
★嘿 小妞，欢迎来到我的洞穴裡★
Aw, yeah, welcome to my crib, girl.
★我们在哪裡？★
Where are we?
★这该怎麼说★
Hey, it's our Fortress of Solitude.
★在霍格华兹魔法学校★
Our Hogwarts.
★在X战警学校★
Our Xavier Academy.
★在星际战舰上！★
State-of-the-art WonderDome!
★我们...★
Ugh.
★该不会在下水道裡吧？★
Are we in the sewer?
★不是的...★
No.
★- 你还是坦白一点吧 - 是的★
- Technically, yes. - Yeah.
★是的，是在下水道★
Yeah, it's a sewer.
★是妳把我们带来这裡的，艾波★
You brought us here, April.
★史林特？★
Splinter?
★你该不会把老爸名字★
How does she know his name?
★告诉她了吧？★
Did you tell her his name?
★她竟然知道★
Maybe she's clairvoyant.
★难道她是绝地武士！★
Maybe she's a Jedi!
★靠近点★
Come closer.
★好久不见了★
It's been a long time.
★嗯...★
Mmm.
★妳眼睛长得和妳爸爸一样★
You always did have your father's eyes.
★我无法理解★
I don't understand.
★别害怕， 所有事情你很快就都清楚了★
Don't be afraid. All will be made clear.
★这实在太疯狂了★
This is crazy.
★你到这裡干嘛？★
★我的徒弟★
★最近发生了一个奇蹟★
There's been a miracle.
★那些给我们製造很多麻烦的守护者★
The vigilantes who've been causing us so much trouble?
★它们曾经是我的实验样品★
They're the test subjects.
★那些我们以為★
Those itty-bitty box turtles
★在大火中丧生的小乌龟★
that we thought we lost in the fire?
★它们还活著，许瑞德大师★
They're alive, Master Shredder.
★然后它们还长大了， 成為...★
And they've grown into something
★非常强大的生物...★
powerful.
★抓到他们当然不容易， 但是如果我们能抓住★
It won't be easy to capture them, but if we can,
★然后把多年以前的★
we can finally carry out the plan
★实验成果提取出来★
that we had all those years ago.
★族将会获得无限的权力和金钱★
★纽约将落入我们手中，许瑞德大师★
The city will be ours.
★欧尼尔是发现他们的人★
O'Neil's daughter was the one who found them
★她也是那个可以引领我们， 找到它们的人★
and she will be the one who will take us right to them.
★发现信号了★
There's the ping.
★我们破解了他们安全防护措施★
We've breached the cloaking security.
★听我说，艾波★
Listen closely, April.
★被带到实验室之前的事情★
I don't remember a time
★我都不记得了★
before living in that laboratory.
★那个命运之夜 就像其他普通夜晚一样开始了★
That fateful night started like any other.
★萨克斯给我们注射了药剂★
Sacks gave us our injections.
★你的父亲监控我们的生命体变化 >★
Your father made sure our vital signs were strong.
★以及你，和平时一样★
And you, as always,
★还是拿著那些食物在喂我们★
provided us with a special treat.
★当我的兄弟们都睡著之后★
After the brothers went to sleep,
★我听到很大的动静★
I heard loud voices.
★到处都是烟雾的气味★
There was the smell of smoke.
★警报的声响★
Alarms sounded.
★你的父亲发现了真相★
Your father had discovered the truth
★他為之工作的那人真相★
behind the man he was working for.
★於是他放火烧了实验室★
He set fire to the lab.
★他用尽最后的力气★
His last breath was taken
★想要摧毁许瑞德的计画★
trying to destroy Shredder's plan.
★我很害怕的时候★
I was terrified.
★但是你却出现了★
But then, you appeared.
★把我们都带到安全的地方★
And ushered us to safety.
★在此之后我都没有机会表达★
I never had a voice then,
★< 但是我现在要谢谢你  艾波★
but I thank you now, April.
★★
Mmm.
★我们在下水道裡游荡, 直到我们发现了这裡★
We wandered the sewers until I found this place.
★当时那突变的物质★
It was then that the mutagen
★那些注射进我们血液的基因★
that was injected into our blood
★开始从各方面改变了我们★
began to change us in miraculous ways.
★我之前见证了你父亲是多麼爱你★
I saw how your father loved you
★我知道我也要对这些乌龟 表示相同的爱护★
and I knew I had to show that same love to the turtles.
★於是我就变成父亲了★
I became their father
★他们成為了我的孩子★
and they became my sons.
★就像每个孩子, 他们受到外界文化的吸引★
Like all children, they were drawn
★我知道总有一天★
to the distractions of popular culture.
★他们想出去探索这个世界★
They would want to explore the world above.
★他们会被世人嘲笑★
They would be ridiculed.
★他们必须学习技能保护自己★
They would need to learn to protect themselves,
★包括精神上和肉体上★
both mentally and physically.
★嘿 你们有人想玩巴巴克吗？★
Hey. Does anyone want to play Buck-Buck?
★一！★
Buck one!
★二！★
Buck two!
★三！★
Buck three!
★你们在做什麼阿？★
Where you going, Raph?
★- 别这样 - 来嘛, 跟著跳阿★
Come on. I can't do it by myself.
★我们需要四个一起！★
I need all four!
★愚蠢的游戏★
You're a Buck short.
★是的， 就像你 愚蠢米奇！★
Yeah, that sounds stupid. Like you, Mikey!
★兄弟们★
That's why you're just the hype man, bra.
★- 你有没有看到那些动作？ - 不要紧的★
- See these moves? - Yeah, whatever, man.
★忍者技艺★
★然后我发现了手册★
And then I found a way.
★首先我得自学成材★
First, I would teach myself the ancient art of Ninjutsu.
★★
Oh!
★他们四个兄弟跟随我的教导★
The brothers followed my lead,
★以飞快的速度进步★
accelerating at a wondrous rate!
★我来无影去无踪★
Wassup, bra? Want some of this?
★就像个幽灵！★
I'm like a ghost!
★我在这，我在这，我就像个影子★
I'm over here, now I'm over here, bra. Like a shadow!
★我就是影子火龙！★
I'm a flame shadow fire dragon!
★他们的天赋也同时是★
Ow!
★他们活力的来源！★
Their gift was also their passion.
★他们在这样的艰苦训练中生活★
They lived, breathed and dreamed
★呼吸以及幻想★
all things martial arts.
★之后★
Then,
★他们终於準备好了★
they were ready.
★武士刀的刀刃闪亮如新★
The katana, most noble of all the blades.
★这是给与领导者的武器★
It is the weapon of a leader.
★所以他们热爱的事物★
Everything they are,
★以及所有他们想成為的事物★
and everything that they've become
★都被你当年所展现出来的勇气， 所拯救而成為现实★
was made possible by the bravery that
★在那个命运决定的夜晚★
you displayed on that fateful night.
★是的，兄弟★
Dude.
★我当时也就是小女孩★
I was just a little girl.
★是你给了我们自由★
And you gave us freedom
★如果换成别人， 可能就把我们关在笼子裡了★
where others would have kept us in cages.
★等等，师父★
Wait a minute, Dad.
★这些年你一直跟我们说的是，那晚★
All these years you told us we were rescued from the fire
★是一个伟大的守护者之魂救我们的， 一个“守护者”★
by a great guardian spirit, the  Hogo-sha.
★现在在你们面前的★
That's right.
★就是守护者★
And this is the  Hogo-sha.
★什麼？★
What?
★原来我的女朋友就是守护者阿★
My girlfriend's totally the  Hogo-sha.
★★
Ow.
★我们有优秀的工程师★
Fortunately, our engineers
★重新打造★
have been making great progress
★你装甲裡面的机械系统★
in refining the robotics in your armor.
★我们要让你装甲性能再度等级★
We're taking it to the next level,
★和古代的优良传统合而為一★
bridging the gap between ancient tradition
★无懈可击★
and modern warfare.
★今晚可以喝乌龟汤了★
★你為什麼要带我来这？★
Why did you bring me here?
★想了解你把我们的存在告诉了谁★
To find out who you told of our existence.
★根本没人相信我 除了艾瑞克?萨克斯★
Nobody that believed me, except for Eric Sacks.
★萨克斯...★
Sacks.
★这就是我最担心的★
Just as I feared.
★萨克斯绝对不是我们的朋友★
Sacks is not a friend.
★他的灵魂已经被污染毒害了★
His soul has been poisoned
★受到了黑暗力量的影响★
by the influence of a dark master.
★许瑞德★
The Shredder.
★许瑞德在日本把萨克斯抚养长大★
Shredder practically raised Sacks in Japan.
★他对於萨克斯就是父亲的存在★
He's like a father to him.
★萨克斯為了他的师父，会做任何事情★
Sacks will do anything for his master.
★等等，等等★
Wait, wait.
★萨克斯和许瑞德？★
Sacks and Shredder?
★那我们為什麼不去把他们杀掉？★
So, why aren't we out there hunting them down?
★拉斐尔★
Because, Raphael,
★因為许瑞德是非常厉害的勇士★
The Shredder is a skilled warrior
★他的残暴程度超乎你的想像！★
whose cruelty is ever-reaching!
★而你们还只是个孩子★
And you are just teenagers.
★在你们血液裡的变种基因， 就是他们正在寻找的东西★
The mutagen in your blood is of great value to them.
★现在萨克斯★
Now that Sacks has confirmation
★已经确认你们的存在★
that you are alive,
★我很担心他们会带来战争★
I fear they will bring the fight to us.
★喔...不会吧...★
Oh, no.
★快点伙计们！★
Stand by to make entry. Let's move!
★快，快，快！★
Go, go, go!
★有入侵 有入侵！★
Perimeter infringe. Breached! We have incoming!
★有敌人进来了★
Oh, no! Oh, no! We got two breaches.
★我们有两处被突破了！★
Fan room, weapons wall!
★米奇，去右边武器室！ 你和多尼跟我来★
Mikey, flank right! Donnie, on me!
★该走了，快点！★
We gotta go! Go, go!
★所有人保持警戒★
Stand by to set charge.
★行动开始，我们开始突袭★
Lock and load. We're going on 10.
★没有生命跡象，继续搜索★
No live ammo. Tranqs only.
★要确保他们活著！★
Take 'em alive!
★不！ 快退回去！★
No! Get back!
★多尼！★
Donnie!
★★
Engage!
★拿下他！★
Get him!
★快过来，过来★
There they are! Neutralize them!
★他们好像很适应黑暗的环境！★
They've got tranq darts!
★记得不要让他们打到你★
Well, don't let them hit your skin.
★我们走！ 动起来！★
Let's go! Let's move!
★那裡！★
Over there!
★在12点方向★
Tango at 12!
★你们好阿，你们觉得可以搞定我？★
Wassup, bra? Oh, you think you can handle this, huh?
★我只要全力穿过去 看我"猛龟出闸"，蠢蛋！★
I'm a snapping turtle, fool. Snap, snap, snap!
★跟你们说过了吧，你们可以吗！★
I meant to do that! I meant to do it!
★我们需要去那边★
We got a breach in the fan room!
★拉飞尔！ 你去那边！★
Raph! Get to the fan room!
★别每次都跟我说我该怎麼做？★
Why are you always telling me what to do?
★照做就对了！ 米奇，你得把艾波带走，快！★
Just go! Mikey, you gotta get April out of here, now!
★包在我身上！★
I got this!
★艾波，跟我来。★
April, come with me.
★我得把你稍微藏起来★
I got a safe place for you to hide.
★如果你渴了★
And if you get thirsty,
★我在冰箱后面藏著柳橙汁★
I got a secret stash of Orange Crush behind the fridge.
★记得不要告诉拉斐尔★
Don't tell Raph.
★许瑞德...★
Shredder.
★这麼多年★
All these years
★我一直试图重製那些变种基因★
I've been trying to recreate the mutagen.
★而你...★
And you?
★你竟然把他们藏在地底下★
You just handed it to me.
★我不会让你对我的儿子们出手的★
You will not lay a hand on my sons.
★你的儿子们？★
Your sons?
★你还真觉得自己是他们的父亲？★
You think you're their father?
★很不错阿，小老鼠！★
Very good, rat!
★师父！★
Sensei!
★多尼！★
Donnie!
★欧尼尔！ 快来这裡！★
Hang on, Leo! Be right there!
★你这个愚蠢的小女孩！★
You stupid little girl!
★艾波！★
April!
★师父！★
Sensei!
★别过来孩子，你退后！★
No, my son, stay back!
★师父！★
Sensei!
★师父！师父！★
Sensei! Dad!
★师父！ 你到底要做什麼？★
Dad! What are you... What are you doing?
★快躲起来！★
Hide!
★不！★
No!
★快自己逃命吧！★
Save yourselves!
★乌龟们，放下武器★
Children, drop your weapons,
★或你的父亲将会死★
or your father will die.
★不！★
No!
★第四个去哪了？★
Where's the fourth?
★他已经死了★
He's dead.
★毁了这个地方★
Destroy this place.
★保持前进！★
Keep moving!
★- 别, 不, 不 - 别推我们★
Stay strong.
★我会记住你们★
Remember, pain's only in the mind.
★进去！★
Move along! Go!
★快进去！★
Troop, go!
★快点！ 快点！★
Move! Move!
★史林特...★
Splinter.
★师父★
Sensei.
Master.
★让我帮你抬出来★
Let's get him to the needle room.
★货物已回收，我们正在路上★
Package is secured. En route.
★我们手上有三个，大概40分内可以抵达★
In approximately 40 minutes.
★把容器都準备好★
Prepare the containment units.
★这些乌龟体内★
Inside those turtles
★有这地球上最珍贵的物质★
is the most precious compound on Earth,
★那些变种基因★
mutagen.
★為了提取那些★
And we will drain every last
★我们会榨乾他们身上每次一滴血★
ounce of their blood to get it,
★即便你们杀了他们我也无所谓★
even if it kills them.
★给我那个急救箱！ 就在架子上！★
Get the first aid kit! On the shelf!
★没事的，没事的★
Hurry. Hurry.
★拉斐尔？★
Raphael?
★我在这★
I'm here.
★你必须去救你的兄弟们★
You must save your brothers.
★阻止许瑞德★
Stop Shredder.
★师父...★
Sensei.
★有什麼警报★
It's some kind of tracker.
★是太罗发过来的！★
It's Donatello!
★快去，拉斐尔★
Go, Raphael.
★我这就去救我的兄弟们★
Let's go save my brothers.
★我们还需要辆车★
We need a ride.
★欧尼尔！★
O'Neil!
★我需要你现在过来★
Look, Vern, I need you to meet me
★请10分鐘之内到★
at Cortlandt Alley in 10 minutes, please.
★等等，為什麼？★
Wait, why?
★我在电话裡不能说★
I can't talk to you about it on the phone.
★你过来就对了★
Just promise you're gonna be there.
★你到底在说什麼？你打过来...★
What do you mean, you can't talk about... You called...
★...我★
...me.
★好吧...你现在想见我了？★
All right. Want me to meet you right now?
★那我就陪你玩玩★
I'll play your little game.
★你怎麼带这帽子？★
What's with the hat?
★我带帽子？★
What is with the...
★好吧...★
I don't know,
★就是想搞点噱头★
it's a buddy of mine's. It's just a goof.
★你要去哪？ 我们要去约会吗？★
What do you want to do? You wanna head downtown?
★萨克斯是為脚族做事的★
Eric Sacks is working with the head of the Foot Clan.
★他刚来★
They just kidnapped the vigilante turtles
★抓走了乌龟们★
to take them to the Sacks estate.
★我们需要尽快赶过去★
We need to go. Come on, Vern.
★喔对对，乌龟们，我都忘了...★
Right, right, right. The turtles. I forgot.
★这实在是太让人难堪了，欧尼尔★
This is getting embarrassing. O'Neil,
★我们都是很不错的成年人★
we're both consenting adults.
★我们都长得不错 你肯定..条件更好...★
We're both very good-looking. You're better, probably.
★我的重点是...★
That's up for debate.
★我们出来约会★
But the point is, we don't need to make up excuses
★- 其实不需要找什麼藉口 - 什麼？★
to hang out with each other. What?
★想花更多时间和我待在一起， 我知道的，也这样想★
You want to spend more time with me. I get it. I would too.
★我们需要现在★
We need to get to the Sacks estate
★就赶紧赶去萨克斯的那边！★
right now, Vern. Come on!
★你一直跟我扯什麼萨克斯的地方， 还有什麼守护者★
"The Sacks estate with the vigilante..."
★- 什麼... - 快开车！★
What... Drive!
★乌龟会说话★
You're a talking turtle.
★是的  我们是会说话的乌龟★
Yeah. Yeah, I'm a talking turtle
★而你是人类怪胎★
and you're a human nerd.
★知道了就快开车★
Now that we got that out of the way, hit it.
★我很抱歉刚刚的行為， 但是有个问题...★
I've never been accused of being a nerd before, but...
★对不起...★
I'm sorry...
★你是怎麼...进来的...★
How did you get in... How did he get in the...
★喔 天啊★
Oh, my.
★★
Wow.
★太难以置信了，你们看看你们自己★
Unbelievable. Let me look at you.
★一般人很难给我留下什麼印象★
I'm a hard guy to impress, but...
★这实在是.....吓到我了...★
This is just... Oh, my God.
★★
Wow!
★之后我们会把你们★
And we were gonna use rabbits!
★当兔子来实验，你们能想像吗？★
Can you imagine that? All we were trying to do
★我们所有想做的，就是创造一个， 万灵药★
is create an antidote.
★為了什麼？★
For what?
★在说一遍我想要多听听你的声音★
Say that again. I want to hear your voice.
★為了什麼？★
For what?
★★
Wow.
★是这样的，我们原来有个计画★
Well, uh, we had this plan.
★一个我们準备重新开始进行的计画， 就在今天★
A plan that we're ready to put back online today.
★我会示范给你们看的，卡拉★
I'll show you. Karai, um...
★让他们看看★
Show them.
★抓住他★
What?
★你知道我自己的建筑  萨克斯大楼吧？★
Do you know my building, Sacks Tower?
★就在楼顶有巨大的建筑★
Got that great big spire up on top?
★那个建筑的裡面...★
That spire is filled...
★装满了数吨的有毒化学物质★
...with tons of chemical toxins.
★不！ 不！★
No! No!
★也就是很残忍的东西★
Bad stuff.
★就像这样残忍★
That kinda bad.
★就在几小时之内★
In a few hours,
★许瑞德就会释放所有的有害物质★
Shredder is going to unleash all that stuff
★遍佈整个城市★
over the whole city. The initial death toll
★而政府将会被这景象深深震撼★
will shake world governments to their core.
★在30天内★
In 30 days,
★纽约将会 成為一个彻底的隔离区★
the city of New York will be a quarantine zone.
★而这时, 我的公司就可以介入了★
And that is where my company comes in.
★我将会用这万灵药★
I'm going to save everyone with the antidote
★拯救美国人民於水火★
that is made from the mutagen
★而解药就是从你们的血液中， 抽取研製而来的★
that is oozing through your blood.
★然后政府就将会给萨克斯集团， 一张任我填写的支票★
The government will then send Sacks Industry a blank check
★之后我就会变富有， 非常的富有★
and I'm going to be rich. Like, stupid rich.
★许瑞德则会驱使这座城市， 按照我们的规则运作★
Shredder will force this city to live under our rule.
★到时候我们就是上帝★
We will be gods.
★我之前曾经想过进行训练...★
Yeah, I've thought about...
★不是说要成為忍者，但是...★
not becoming a ninja, but I was doing a bunch of yoga
★但是我有训练，比如说连续练习瑜伽10天...★
for like, 10 days at one point, and, uh, I pulled a hamstring.
★- 我们到了 - 就是那裡★
There's the gate right there. There it is.
★就这样撞进去★
Ram the gate.
★" 撞进去 " ? 这是第6频道的财產阿★
"Ram the gate"? This is Channel 6 property.
★我说了冲进去！★
I said ram the gate!
★好吧，大家抓紧了！★
All right, everybody, strap in!
★喔 该死的！★
Oh, shit!
★上，上，上，上！★
Go, go, go, go!
★跟著我！★
Follow me!
★东西给我★
I'll take this canister to New York
★我带去纽约继续研究基因★
to withdraw the mutagen.
★确保你们把他们所有的血液都抽乾★
Make sure that you drain all their blood.
★是时候干掉剩下的那个大傢伙了★
Time to take a bite out of the Big Apple.
★嗨！ 滚离这裡！★
Hey! Get out of here!
★李奥！★
Leo!
★来的真是时候★
About time.
★什麼...★
What the...
★拉斐尔...★
Raphael.
★很高兴你能来这加入我们★
Glad you could join us.
★第四个笼子，已经為你準备好了★
The fourth cage is for you.
★这一下真够痛的，兄弟★
That's harsh, man.
★那隻老鼠，根本没有把你们教好★
The rat did not teach you well!
★拉斐尔！★
Raphael!
★你...★
You.
★你专心跟我打★
Focus on me.
★四个会说话的乌龟★
Three... Four total turtles.
★打一个机器武士... 有何不可...★
One's fighting a robot samurai. Why not?
★多尼！★
Donnie!
★多尼！我应该怎麼做★
★- 肾上腺素。 - 你说什麼？★
Adrenaline. What?
★肾上腺素★
Adrenaline.
★没问题★
All right. All right.
★警告 - 心臟 心跳减慢★
★肾上腺素。★
Adrenaline.
★他这样会杀了他的★
He's going to kill him.
★警告 - 肾上腺素 过量风险★
★快起来阿！★
Get up!
★真的奏效了★
It's working.
★我觉得我们应该先迴避一下★
I think we should move.
★哇现在感觉好爽阿★
Oh! I feel really good right now! I feel like running!
★我感觉好像在七重天★
I feel like cleaning! Who wants to clean the dojo?
★感觉像是上了天堂！★
I'll clean the dojo!
★嘿 拉斐尔还躺在那！★
Endorphins! Endorphins!
★嘿 拉斐尔！★
We got to get Raph!
★拉斐尔！ 拉斐尔！★
Raph! Raph!
★你没问题吗？ 你死吗？ 你没问题吗？★
Are you okay? Are you dead? Are you okay?
★快来 快走★
Come on. Come on.
★- 去哪？ - 去萨克斯大楼！★
- Go where? - Sacks Tower!
★在纽约★
New York City! Times Square!
★许瑞德去释放毒气去了！★
Shredder's going to release a toxin!
★他要让全城中毒！★
It's gonna poison the whole city!
★然后萨克斯要去卖解药！★
And Sacks is gonna sell the antidote!
★他说解药在我们的血液裡 所以他现在就要过去那裡了★
That's in our blood! So we've got to get going now!
★- 没错 - 让我们為了师父报仇★
Good. Let's do it for  sensei.
★好的，我们出发吧！★
Okay. We're going!
★所以人都冷静，希望就在我们身上了★
Everybody calm down! Look how calm I am!
★我们速度得快点了，我们走★
We got to move. Let's go!
★萨克斯坐直升机走了！★
Sacks is airborne!
★他飞过去只要19分鐘！★
Flight time to Manhattan, 19 minutes!
★我们先从这离开，多尼！★
Get us out of here, Donnie!
★扫描中★
★不是吧!，敌人来了！★
Oh, my gosh, they have guns!
★快趴下！★
Get down!
★你们没事吧？★
Ha! Are you guys okay?
★原来我们还能防弹★
We're bulletproof.
★水啦！★
Sweet!
★我们要抢到那辆卡车！★
Advance and engage!
★你能驾驶那卡车吗？★
Can you drive that truck?
★耶！★
Yeah!
★好的，準备，拉斐尔, 好了吗？★
We're on Raph. Ready?
★快来！★
Come on!
★所有人都上卡车，我们得出发了！★
Everybody in the truck! We gotta go, go, go! Move!
★你会开这玩意对吧？★
Vern, you know how to drive this, right?
★是的是的, 所以我要★
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just got to hotwire this thing, I guess.
★把下面线拆了点火就能走了★
Classic blue wire/red wire situation.
★- 钥匙！ - 是的★
Keys! Yeah.
★钥匙比较好★
Keys are better.
★- 快开车！ - 我上面！★
Drive! I'm on it!
★我需要的只是后座 那一堆会开车会说话的乌龟★
That's all I need is a backseat-driving talking turtle!
★- 我们出发！ - 快追！★
- Let's go! - Move!
★- 往你们正前方开 - 收到★
- Jackal-One-Tango, on your 12! -  Copy that.
★抱歉之前怀疑你★
I shouldn't have doubted you.
★我还以為你疯了★
Sorry I didn't stick up for you.
★不过这实在很疯狂★
I can't believe that you're not crazy! How crazy is that?
★目标在正前方！★
Target, 12 o'clock!
★伙伴们我们现在到底是去哪？★
Where are we going, guys?
★多尼，最好回到曼哈顿的路线是什麼？★
Donnie, what's the fastest way back to Manhattan?
★我们只要沿著目前路线前进★
We just need to stay on this road.
★如果能到达★
If we can get to the maintenance hatch
★山下那个维修机房★
at the bottom of the hill,
★那有个下水道就距离这裡2.4公里★
there's a sewer line 2.4 miles from here.
★米奇！ 我们得让他们知道一下！★
Mikey! Let them know up there!
★我上来了！★
I'm on it!
★哦，不是吧...★
Oh, no.
★凡恩，快快快，往右开！★
Vern, go, go, go, go, go!
★我上面！★
I'm on it!
★停止！★
Stop!
★凡恩，快踩煞车！★
Vern, hit the brakes!
★错误的方法！ 错误的方法！★
Wrong way! Wrong way!
★他们下去了！ 快追！★
Go around! Go, go, go!
★李奥，躲开！★
Leo, move, move!
★什麼？★
What?
★★
Opposite, opposite, opposite!
★哦，不！★
Oh, no!
★我们偏离了多远？★
How far off course are we?
★我们现在绝对是在抄近路★
Actually, we're on a bit of a shortcut.
★但是我们其实是需要从这山上下去★
But we need to keep going down.
★我意思是直直地往下走★
Straight down.
★嗨！★
Hey!
★尽量...保持★
Just keep
★向前...开！★
going straight!
★你好阿美女★
What's up, angel cakes?
★该死！★
Fire!
★伙伴们! 李奥，有麻烦了！★
Guys, Leo's in trouble!
★我的壳刚才破了★
My shell's cracked. Just tape it up.
★- 这次得靠你了 - 看来我得出一次锋头了★
Allow me to be the bad-ass for once.
★抓住，李奥，别害怕，我来帮你了★
Hang on, Leo. Disengaging.
★我其实一直都想试著这麼玩一下★
God, I've always wanted to try this.
★我抓住你了，兄弟， 搞定一个，还剩下两个★
I got you, brother. One car down, two to go.
★米奇！★
Mikey!
★- 好吧  坚持住 - 我这就来了！★
All right, that's it. I'll take it from here!
★★
Whoo-hoo!
★伙伴们，我正在开车呢！★
Raph, I'm driving! Yeah!
★★
Whoo-hoo!
★欧尼尔，妳在干嘛？★
O'Neil, what are you doing?
★很好继续拍，不要漏掉任何镜头★
Yeah, that's good. Make sure you're getting everything.
★凡恩！★
Vern!
★欧尼尔！ 把手给我！★
O'Neil! Give me your arm!
★凡恩！★
Vern!
★雪崩来了！★
Avalanche!
★★
Whoa!
★快点李奥，快点醒来！★
Come on, Leo, wake up!
★如果你醒来★
Yeah! If you wake up,
★任何都你说了算！★
I promise to do anything you say!
★许瑞德的直升机★
Guys! Shredder's chopper is 20 miles
★现在距离纽约那边还有32公里！★
outside of New York City airspace!
★谢谢你的直升机状态更新，多尼★
Thanks for the traffic update, Donnie.
★现在的重点是我们之后要干嘛？★
You doing sports and weather next?
★坏消息★
If you're gonna be nasty about it
★是53秒内★
then I guess you don't want to know
★你会看到悬崖★
that there's a 500-foot drop-off in 53 seconds!
★你是说有悬崖...★
Are you saying there's...
★我醒过来了！★
A cliff!
★我们得把艾波救出来， 把你的手给我★
We gotta get April out of there! Raph, heads up!
★别忘记还有一个老男人！★
Don't forget that old guy!
★- 李奥 - 嘿，计画有变★
Hi. Change of plans. Oh, come on.
★- 喔，不是吧 - 快趴下★
Guys, get down! Get down!
★还有12秒我们就要掉下去了！★
Twelve seconds and we're going over!
★嘿 多尼，快玩那招花俏的弹射技！★
Hey, Donnie, do that fancy slingshot thing!
★我得把那台车给解决了！★
We got to take Little Miss Sunshine out!
★抓紧了！★
Batter up!
★快抓住绳子！★
Grab on.
★米奇！ 抓住绳子！★
Mikey! Grab the cable!
★我抓到它！ 我抓到它！★
I got it! I got it!
★等等！ 等等！★
Hold on! Hold on!
★哦，不！★
Oh, no!
★不，不，不！★
No, no, no!
★哦，不...★
Oh, no...
★李奥，艾波...★
Poor Leo, April...
★还有那个不知名的男人...★
And that other guy.
★他们还那麼年轻， 那麼漂亮★
They were so young, so beautiful.
★- 那麼漂亮 - 别废话了，蠢蛋★
They ain't dead, numb nuts.
★喔，你们还活著阿★
Oh. Right on.
★我希望你的壳裡藏著一个降落伞★
I hope you got a parachute under that shell.
★- 伙伴们！ - 那是维修机房！★
Hey, guys! It's the maintenance hatch!
★真是一次绝妙的反击行动阿！★
Our ticket home!
★别废话了，拉我们上去！★
A little help, please!
★伙伴们，我们有麻烦了, 许瑞德已经到纽约了★
Guys, we gotta hustle. Shredder's over New York City!
★老师，我们还有4分鐘抵达★
Sensei, the mutagen is four minutes out.
★正按照计画前进★
Moving forward as planned.
★请乘客★
Please keep your arms and legs
★请勿把手脚伸出壳外★
inside the shell at all times.
★另一则更新★
Satellite imagery shows
★许瑞德已经在萨克斯大楼顶端了★
Shredder's reached the top of Sacks Tower.
★如果他释放了毒气那城市就完了★
If that's where he's releasing the toxin from...
★那城市就完了！★
It's gonna spread all over the city!
★我们得...★
We need to...
★好了，都听著！★
...break a left!
★我们需要找到通往屋顶的电梯★
We gotta find the elevators and get up to the roof.
★你们离开这裡， 跑到安全的距离外躲起来★
You guys get out of here. Get to a safe distance.
★不，不，我们可以去找萨克斯★
No, no, we can go find Sacks
★然后得到解药，就当作备用计画★
and get our hands on the mutagen as a contingency plan,
★就是以防万一★
just in case... You know.
★谢谢你们的那份勇气★
Thanks for the vote of confidence.
★如果我们回不来， 把万灵药带去给史林特★
If we don't make it back, bring the mutagen to Splinter.
★万灵药可以救活他★
It can save his life.
★萨克斯在36楼的实验室★
Sacks's laboratory's on the 36th floor.
★我已经关掉所有保安系统了★
I've already disabled the security system.
★对了  ...★
Oh, and, uh...
★祝好运★
Good luck!
★如果我回不来，你要记得我，艾波★
If I don't return, remember me, April.
★你可以永远在你心裡★
You can always find me
★找到我★
in here.
★我们也走吧★
You're a complicated chick.
★很好★
Yeah.
★电梯就在转角！★
Elevator's just around this corner!
★大家听好了★
All right, guys, listen up.
★照我的计画就不会失败★
We stick to my plan and we won't fail.
★三秒后冲出去★
Fan out in three, two, one.
★★
Whoa.
★那裡不是电梯啦★
Not the elevator.
★真的不是★
Nope.
★第一个容器开始注入解药★
The first vial is filling with antidote now.
★开始啟动毒气释放程序★
Initiating the toxin release procedure.
★嘻哈米奇★
MC Mikey.
★嘻哈★
MC
★準备， 摆好阵仗！★
Ready, stance!
★嘿 米奇，记得那★
Hey, Mikey, remember that thing you used to say
★你记得小时候喊的那句话吗？★
when we were kids?
★你要我保证别在说的★
You made me promise never to say it again.
★忘了那回事★
Forget about that.
★想不想来喊一下？★
Still got one in the tank?
★我肖想很久了★
I've been holding it in for years.
★兄弟们，我们需要...★
Guys, we need a plan!
★- 卡哇邦嘎！ - 兄弟们 你们要干嘛★
Cowabunga!
★李奥！★
Leo!
★我们这有情况★
Yeah, we got a 10-10.
★楼顶有残骸掉落★
Debris falling from the building.
★快点★
Come on.
★我来搞定这个，伙伴们★
I got this, guys! I'll take him!
★来吧！★
Come on!
★哦，不，你没有！★
Oh, no, you don't!
★说真的★
Seriously,
★你们俩...★
you two...
★真是让人尊敬阿，真的★
You're adorable, really.
★我都能感受到你们的魄力★
I could just pinch your cheeks!
★兄弟们， 他来了，他来了！★
Ugh, guys, he's coming, he's coming!
★兄弟们！★
Guys!
★多尼！★
Donnie!
★抓紧，抓紧！★
Come on, come on!
★抓紧阿，李奥！★
Hold on, Leo!
★我充分理解你想為你爸爸报仇的心情★
I understand a girl with dead daddy issues.
★但是你阻止不了我★
I do. But you're not gonna stop me.
★这只不过是★
This is history
★歷史重演而已★
repeating itself.
★你的父亲也想阻止我， 艾波，就像你现在一样★
Your father walked in on me, April, just like you did.
★我不得不开枪杀了他★
It took a few less bullets to take him down, though.
★你杀了我父亲★
You killed my father.
★快点！ 快点！★
Move! Move!
★快，快，快！★
Go, go, go!
★来吧，兄弟们！★
Come on, guys!
★抓到你了！★
Got you!
★够了没，这堂课已经结束了★
Enough. The lesson is over.
★我们被扁的太惨了★
Ugh! We're getting our asses kicked out there.
★剩下50多秒的时间毒气就要释放了★
We only got 50 more seconds before the toxin's released.
★★
Hey.
★你们谁想玩巴巴克啊？★
Who wants to play Buck-Buck?
★巴巴克？★
Buck-Buck?
★- 什麼？ - 你说什麼？★
What? Buck-Buck. Tony-on-a-Pony.
★★
Some people call it Johnnie-on-a-Rock.
★等等...★
Wait.
★对★
Yeah.
★让我们来玩巴巴克★
Let's play Buck-Buck.
★- 但是我们為什麼要... - 不...★
But why would we... No.
★我会按照李奥的做★
We do what Leo says.
★我们是一体的★
Lead the way.
★欧尼尔！★
O'Neil!
★★
Argh!
Hmm.
★★
Oh!
★卡哇邦嘎！★
Cowabunga.
★你没事吧？★
Are you okay?
★把万灵药带上，去找人来帮忙★
Look, just go get some help and take the mutagen with you.
★走阿，快点走！★
Just go. Go! No!
★这是我难得耍帅的一天， 可是我起不来★
Just another day in the life of a man of action.
★哦不，好痛★
Ow. No, I'm not getting up.
★你知道怎麼解除这东西吗？★
You know how to use this thing?
★这是古董了★
It's a simple command-line interface.
★这东西★
No one's used this code in 15 years.
★是15年前的技术了★
I mean, I've read about it online.
★我只有在网路看过...★
But these kind of things take time.
★这很困难阿★
Thinking there was no way I'd ever be in a position
★我从来就没有...★
where the fate of an entire city...
★我去帮你争取一些时间★
I'll buy you some time.
★5秒之后将释放毒气★
Toxin disbursement
★在五，四★
in five, four,
★三★
three,
★二★
two...
★搞定，危机解除！ 你们争取的时间很宝贵★
Bam! System disabled! Who wants Italian?
★為你们每个人喝采！★
I'm buying! Tiramisu for everybody! Ah!
★★
Ah.
★这座塔要倒了！★
Fall in!
★等等！撑住！撑住！★
Hold on! Hold it! Hold it!
★如果毒气瓶落地摔破★
If the spire falls and the toxin makes ground impact,
★也会污染城市！★
it'll contaminate a 10-block radius!
★我们能把它这样守住的机率有多大？★
What are the odds of us stopping that from happening?
★0.0000000000003%!★
Uh, 0.00000000003%!
★那我还是赌一把吧 现在开始所以人坚守住，都不能动★
I'll take it. Nobody moves, no matter what.
★我说，李奥...★
But, Leo...
★我说了所有人都不许动！★
I said nobody moves!
★李奥，让我去！★
Leo, I'm letting go!
★★
Ah!
★许瑞德！★
Shredder!
★这是唯一剩下的！★
This is all that's left!
★又是你这小女孩★
Little girl.
★这是我的东西★
That belongs to me.
★撑住了，要撑住阿★
Hold on! Hold on! Hold it!
★退后！所有人都退后！★
Get back! All the way back!
★艾波！★
April!
★来吧, 兄弟们！★
Come on, guys!
★★
Ah!
★艾波！★
April!
★抓到你了，拉斐尔！★
Got you, Raph!
★抓紧了！抓紧了！ 艾波！★
Hold on! Hold on! April!
★我抓到你了★
I got you.
★把我甩过去！★
Swing me towards him!
★照她说的做！★
Do it!
★李奥！★
Leo!
★终於搞定了，就是这样★
That's my girl.
★我觉得我们大限将至！★
I think this is it, guys!
★有人有什麼遗言要说的吗？★
Does anyone have anything they want to say?
★多尼？★
Donnie?
★每天早上★
I'm the one who licks the icing
★我都会偷舔糖霜★
off the Pop-Tarts every morning
★再把他们放回原处★
and puts them back in the box.
★不，不，不，不！★
No, no, no, no!
★我还是青少年不想那麼早死啊★
I so did not understand the ending of  Lost.
★拉斐尔？★
Raph?
★我只是想说★
I just, uh...
★如果这是我们大家最后一刻★
If this is our last moment together,
★我只想让你们知道我很抱歉★
I just want you guys to know I'm sorry.
★我很抱歉，我不应该对你们那麼严苛的★
I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
★每次我逼迫你们的时候...★
Every time I pushed you, I... I threatened you,
★我朝你怒吼，逼你们突破极限★
I yelled at you, I pushed you beyond your limits,
★只是因為我相信你们！★
it was because I believe in you!
★相信你们每个人！★
I believe in each one of you!
★我相信你们的信念★
I believe in your spirit and your intelligence
★精神和潜能★
and your potential.
★而每次我说著要离开★
And every time I talked about walking away,
★是因為我很害怕★
it was because I was scared!
★我只是觉得★
I just didn't think I was good enough
★我逐渐不配站在你们身旁★
to stand next to you
★称呼你们為兄弟， 我必须告诉你们★
and call you brothers and say to you
★我爱你们！★
I love you!
★我非常爱你们每个人★
I love you guys so much!
★拉斐尔...？★
Raph?
★我们成功了★
We made it.
★你在哭吗？★
Are you crying?
★才不是，只是灰尘太多了★
No, ding-dong. It's just a little dusty out here.
★好了，★
Okay, the mutagen is now
★现在万灵药进入他的血液了★
entering his bloodstream.
★史林特师父？★
Master Splinter?
★没事情发生★
Nothing's happening.
★為什麼他还不见效果？★
Why isn't it working yet?
★米奇...★
Mikey...
★米奇，靠近点听我说★
Huh? Mikey, come closer.
★- 他说什麼？ - 他说什麼？★
What did he say? What did he say?
★他说: 你别跪在我的胸口上★
He said, "Please get your knee off my chest."
★师父！★
Sensei!
★你还活著！★
You're alive!
★它见效了！★
It worked!
★这都是我的错★
I'm sorry. This was all my fault.
★你是对的， 我们还没準备好★
You were right. We weren't ready.
★不对，是我并没有準备好★
No.
★去做好準备让你们离开★
It was I who wasn't ready to let you go.
★所有你们需要做的★
All you needed was to discover
★就是发现在你们身上潜在的真正力量★
that your true power lies in believing in one another.
★看吧她来了★
There she is.
★纽约的秘密武器你好★
New York's secret weapon.
★你的手怎麼样了，凡恩★
How's your arm, Vern?
★是阿， 如果我不选择冲上去的话，也就不会受伤了★
Well, it wouldn't be much use in a fight.
★虽然我以前的确不会这样鲁莽★
Not that I was much use before, but...
★- 你有辆新车了 - 是阿★
Did you get a new car? Yeah.
★这辆是我们的新的新闻车★
You're looking at the new Fenwick Express.
★看起来不错吧★
Pretty sweet, huh?
★还改装了一下★
Kind of an upgrade.
★我想我需要在除了我工作的车之外★
I figured I'd need new wheels
★自己也弄一辆新车来开开★
after my old work vehicle went boom.
★第6频道给了我这个★
Yeah, Channel 6 gave it to me.
★他们说千万别刮花了★
They said don't put a scratch on it,
★它的速度是原本的两倍多★
but, like, lightning's going to strike twice?
★所以你把我叫到这裡是為什麼★
So, is that why you called me here,
★就為了聊你的新车？★
to talk about your new car?
★我想你不是很热衷於★
I know that you're not exactly
★被请客吃饭的那一类女孩★
a fancy restaurant kind of girl, so I figured
★所以我觉得★
a creepy underpass in an abandoned neighborhood
★约你来这个废弃的工地★
in the middle of the night was more your speed.
★会让我看起来很更酷★
I wanted you to be comfortable.
★艾波艾波艾波，DJ米奇来了！★
DJ Mikey in the house!
★你们几个在这干嘛？★
What are you guys doing here?
★我发觉我们还欠你个人情， 帮我们保守我们的秘密★
We figured we owed you a thanks for keeping our secret.
★如果你把我们的消息卖给人类， 你可以大赚一笔，★
You had a lot to gain from telling people about us,
★但是你保护了我们★
but you had our backs.
★是阿 朋友就是用来彼此守护的， 拉斐尔★
Yeah, 'cause that's what family's for, Raph.
★你们也弄一辆车了？★
So you guys are driving now?
★裡面有液晶电视★
Yeah, man. I pimped this bad boy out.
★製冰机★
Got a 42-inch plasma with the
★7.1杜比环绕音响★
NBA package, shave ice machine,
★NBA篮球门票★
7.1 digital surround sound.
★看看这东西，兄弟★
Check the bass, bra.
★★
Uh-oh.
Ooh.
★是我的错，我没搞清楚要按哪个钮★
My bad. I'm still figuring out the buttons.
★这是我的新车阿！★
That was my new Fenwick Express!
★我才刚拿到它阿★
I just... I just got that.
★我们该走了，需要载你回家吗？★
We better get out of here. Want a ride home?
★不用了...我和他坐地铁回家吧★
You know what? I think we're gonna take the subway.
★我们坐地铁★
We're going to take the subway.
★你确定吗？★
You sure?
★我特地為你做了一首歌★
I got a real nice song that's all cued up.
★為了你这个特别的女孩★
- It's special, girl. - No, don't.
★- 為了我们俩 - 别搞了 米奇★
- For us. - Come on, Mikey.
★- 不，不，不， -女孩 听听我的承诺★
No, no, no, Mikey, you promised.
★- 虽然我很花心, 自从遇到妳 - 停止唱歌★
? Imagine me and you I do
★我就想唱歌给你听, 请你别怀疑★
? I think about you day and night It's only right
★现在就我就在这裡★
? To think about... ?
★希望你会接受我！★
I'm making really good headway!
★快点闭嘴, 米奇！★
Shut up, Mikey!
★噢…已经决定了★
? I can't see me loving nobody but you
★我这一生非你不娶★
? For all my life
★你的笑容★
? When you're with me, baby
★美得就像晴空万里★
? The skies'll be blue For all my life! ?
★**********★